# **Cameron West**

Game Developer & Software Engineer

cgwest00@gmail.com https://www.cgwe.st/ linkedin.com/in/cameron-west-964698204

#### SUMMARY

Passionate and results-driven game developer and software engineer with demonstrated experience in improving performance, testing existing code, and developing new features. Expert in Java and C++ with working knowledge of many other programming languages. Possesses excellent communication skills, strong attention to detail, and ability to finish projects on schedule.

## **SKILLS**

C/C++	C#	git	HTML/CSS
Java	JavaScript	0penGL	Python
Rust	Unity	Unreal	Visual Studio

## **EXPERIENCE**

### Aveva Software, Lake Forest

- Software Engineering Intern

June 2022 - PRESENT

- Developed a web-based graphic editing app using Blazor and Web Assembly
- Prototyped a new client-server model with a 13x performance improvement
- Created debugging tools to assist other members of the team
- Diagnosed and fixed path traversal vulnerabilities
- Assisted with the development of testing tools to simulate 1000+ concurrent users
- Collaborated with team members using git and Azure DevOps
- Set up many Azure Pipelines for static code analysis
- Followed the Scrum framework and the Agile development methodology

## University of California, Santa Cruz

- Research Assistant

March 2022 - June 2022

- Generated 3D models of human faces with different methods of photogrammetry
- Developed an Android app to generate dense point arrays and 3D objects
- Created Python and Bash scripts to parse various data
- Collaborated with others for data collection and analysis

### **PROJECTS**

#### Space Shark

- Zero Gravity FPS
- Created in Unreal 5.1
- Lead programmer using Blueprint and C++
- Designed procedural and generative sounds using MetaSounds
- Version management using Perforce Helix

## Thimble Knight

- 2.5D Platformer
- Created using the Unity game engine and C#
- Worked with the artist team to create processes for collaboration
- Programming lead for a team of 7
- Concurrent development with Git and GitHub

### Night Drive

- Retrowave Graphics Demo
- Created with JavaScript and WebGL via the THREE.js library
- Custom vertex and fragment GLSL shaders for procedurally generated terrain using Perlin noise

#### Celestial Combat

- Pixel Art Shoot 'Em Up
- Created with JavaScript and Phaser 3
- Programmer for a team of 3
- Set up processes for art integration
- Combination of object-oriented and functional programming styles
- Version management with Git and GitHub

# Ray Tracer

- From-scratch 3D Graphics Renderer
- Programmed in C++
- Extensive use of linear algebra
- Multi-threading support
- Modular scene construction
- Supports several image formats

#### Music Runner

- First-Person Rhythm Game
- Built with Unity and C#
- Extensive file processing for procedural level generation based
- Dynamic, audio-reactive post-processing effects
- Heavily modified an existing wall-running movement system

## **EDUCATION**

# University of California, Santa Cruz

- B.S. Computer Science: Game Design

September 2020 - June 2023

- 3.93 Cumulative GPA, Magna Cum Laude
- Dean's Honors recipient every quarter
- Experienced with 3D math and linear algebra
- Gained broad experience with various programming languages and libraries
- Developed a custom 3D game engine with lighting, shadows, and particles
- Designed video games in Unity and Unreal for senior-year projects